ortsbo.com 2015-02-24

# Privacy Policy - Ortsbo, Inc.

Ortsbo Inc. (“Ortsbo” or “Company”) understands that privacy is very important to you. As a part of providing our services, products and operating our websites, the Company collects certain personal and non-personal information from you. This Privacy Policy is designed to explain to you what kind of information the Company collects, how it is used and how the Company endevours to keep the information secure.

## What Types of Information Does Ortsbo Collect?

Ortsbo collects both personal and non-personal (aggregate) information from you in a variety of ways. Personal information will be gathered should you choose to register with Ortsbo or order products or services from the Company. This personal and non-personal information will be gathered via a registration process and/or via the operation or use of services or by the use of cookies or other similar technologies during your site visits. This information may include:

1\. Personal Data: Should you choose to register, you will be asked your first and last name, email address, country of residence, language preferences, gender, zip/postal code and year of birth. We will keep records of any products or services you order from us or from our third party partners. We may also collect information from you when you complete customer surveys, participate in promotions or participate in our Live & Global events. As part of the operation of the services, we will also keep records regarding your usage of Company services, which may include the content of any messages sent or received by you.

2\. Personal Financial Data: If you choose at any time to access any Company’s subscriber or premium services where a cost may be involved, or order products from Company, we may ask you for your Pay Pal Account, Credit Card Information or other relevant financial information.

3\. Aggregate or Anonymous Data: As part of our operations, the Company will collect IP addresses and may also collect data from the operation of cookies, .gifs, web beacons, Pixel Tags and similar technologies. More information about these types of technologies is provided below. We will also collect aggregate data about patterns of usage of the services.

### How Does Ortsbo Make Use of Your Personal Data?

The collection of information by the Company facilitates a robust, efficient, and rewarding communications experience. Some of the uses include: providing technical assistance and support, providing service updates, processing and delivering purchases and orders made via the Company’s site or otherwise, providing the services, resolving disputes, verifying identities, improving the design, layout and functionality of the Company’s communications platform, protecting and fighting against fraud, and enforcing and policing the End User Licensing Agreement (“EULA”). The Company may also access or disclose information about you, including the content of your communications, in order to: (a) comply with the law or respond to lawful requests or legal process; (b) protect the rights or property of Ortsbo Inc. or our customers, including the enforcement of our agreements or policies governing your use of the service; or (c) when we believe such access or disclosure is necessary to protect the personal safety of Ortsbo Inc. employees, customers or the public.

The Company may also use personal information to provide you with information about other products or services offered by Company or to invite you to participate in promotions. This may include providing relevant advertising and/or related links to you based on your IP address, content of messages and other information related to your use of the services.

## Use of Cookies

Like many other sites Ortsbo uses cookies, which are small data files that may be stored on the users computers hard drive. A cookie may contain identifying information that may assist web applications in identifying you and/or your computer and/or your preferences. Most of the browsers available today will have the option to disable cookies altogether, or notify you if you receive a new cookie or prevent your system from accepting new cookies. Please be cognizant of the fact that if you choose to disable cookies some portion of the services may not function properly or not function at all.

Many of the advertisements that you see on the Ortsbo interface are delivered by third party web advertising partners. The web advertising partners may use cookies to generate information, such as the number of time your visit a particular site but they will not obtain your name, address or other personal information. Cookies in this case are used to serve advertisements and/or promotions to you and track those advertisements/promotions. If you want more information regarding the collection and use of cookies by third party advertisers, please visit http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp

## Sharing of Your Personal Data

Ortsbo does not rent, trade, barter, sell, make available or transfer any of your personal data, communications or traffic data to any third parties without your permission except in certain limited circumstances.

1\. We may be obliged under certain laws or by court orders from competent authorities to transfer your personal data, communications and/or traffic data without your permission or prior knowledge. The Company may receive requests from state of federal law enforcement organizations or a court or another authority or regulatory agency with appropriate jurisdiction to retain or provide personal data, and/or traffic data and/or communications content. We will provide this data and any assistance needed in order to fufill the request.

2\. In order to efficiently provide the service(s) that you have requested from Company or to assist Company with policing and preventing fraud, it may be necessary to share your personal and traffic data with vendors or other service providers, partners, carriers, distributors, banking and/or payment processing organizations. The Company requires that all third party organizations take appropriate measures and observe all relevant legislation in the jurisdiction/area they operate to protect your personal and traffic data.

3\. We may also share your personal information for the provision of requested services that originate with a related or affiliated company.

4\. In the event that Ortsbo acquires a similar operating business or is acquired by another business organization, personal information of Ortsbo’s users will generally be considered an asset and will be subject to transfer to a third party as part of the transaction. Ortsbo reserves the right to include users personal information as part of any such transaction.

Ortsbo reserves the right to share aggregated and anonymous information with third parties for marketing, research or any other purpose.

## Where will your Personal Information Be Processed?

Your personal data, communications and traffic data may be processed and stored in any country where the Company operates and/or maintains a facility. This may include areas outside North America. By using the services offered by Company you expressly agree to the transfer of information/data outside of your country of residence.

## Protecting Your Personal Information

Ortsbo and all related companies engage in appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect personal data, communications and traffic data provided to or collected by Ortsbo. We use industry-standard tools to ensure that your information is secure and confidential. You should not share passwords or other confidential information about your account.

## How Long is Your Personal Data Held By Ortsbo?

Ortsbo will keep your personal information as long as necessary to complete any of the purposes of this privacy policy and will comply with all applicable rules and regulation that govern minimum length of holding of personal information.

## Changing or Updating Your Personal Information

You may contact Ortsbo at support@Ortsbo.com to view, rectify, adjust or complete your personal data. Upon verification of your identity and within a reasonable period of time, Ortsbo will comply with your request, provided that in doing so it does not contravine any applicable laws or legislation.

## Contacting You

Ortsbo may from time to time contact you and/or send you messages concerning service issues, updates, patches and/or other information that we feel is relevent to provide you with optimal service. Ortsbo reserves the right to contact you via email or the Company’s messaging service for operational purposes, as well as matters such as violations of third party rights, violations of the End User Licensing Agreement and violations of the privacy policy.

Ortsbo may also use email or the Company’s messaging service to update you with news about the products and services that you have purchased or are using and/or to inform you about other Ortsbo products, unless you have opted out of receiving this information. To opt out of receiving this type of information please contact Ortsbo at privacy@Ortsbo.com.

## Contacting Friends and Their Personal Data

You may wish to inform your friends of the services provided by Ortsbo. In this regard Ortsbo may provide a referral service for you to use. The only time that this information will be used is to generate an email message from Ortsbo to these potential users of the Ortsbo service.

## Linked Websites

The Ortsbo interface may contain links that allow you to leave the Company website and access another website(s). These websites will have a different privacy policy and are not under control of Company. Any personal information gathered by these companies is subject to their privacy policies and Ortsbo is not responsible for such personal data.

## Changes to Privacy Policy

The Company reserves the right to change, alter, modify or adjust the Privacy Policy.  
We will notify users about changes in this the revised Privacy Policy by publishing a copy of it at [www.ortsbo.com/privacy-policy/](http://www.ortsbo.com/privacy).

This revised Privacy Policy will become effective 30 (thirty) days after it has been published unless you accept the revised privacy policy.

Privacy Policy Last Amended: July 6, 2010

**© ORTSBO INC.**

Ortsbo Inc., 30 West Beaver Creek Road,

Unit 111, Richmond Hill,

Ontario, Canada L4B 3K1
